slimmingworld.com 2017-06-21

# Slimming World - The UK's favorite way to lose weight is now in the USA.

This Policy tells you, among other things, what information we gather from you through our Site, how we may use or disclose that information, and our efforts to protect it.

This Policy effective as of July 11, 2016.

### Privacy Policy

Miles Bramwell USA, LLC, a Texas limited liability company, d/b/a Slimming World (“Slimming World”, “us”, “we,” or  “our”), has created this Privacy Policy (“Policy”) in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of your personal information. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website (the “Site”).

This Policy tells you, among other things, what information we gather from you through our Site, how we may use or disclose that information, and our efforts to protect it.

BY USING OUR SITE, YOU ARE ACCEPTING THE PRACTICES SET OUT IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY, OUR TERMS OF USE AGREEMENT, AND FOR REGISTERED MEMBERS, OUR USER SUBSCRIPTION AGREEMENT.

### 1\. Notice of Information Collected and Disclosed

In connection with your use of our Site, we may collect the following information:

  * The e-mail addresses of users who communicate with us via the Site or via e-mail;
  * Information volunteered or submitted by the user, such as: 
    * “Personally Identifiable Information” (“PII”) including information you provide when you register with the Site that can be used to identify you, such as your name, address, date of birth, mobile phone number or email address. While your IP address may not be considered PII on its own, when it is combined with certain other identifiers, it may become PII.
    * “Account Identifiers,” such as your username, password, or credit card information;
    * “Account preferences,” such as how often you wish to receive email notifications and which information you choose to share with the community; or
    * “Health Information”, such as your weight and height, diseases you have been diagnosed with, symptoms, moods and other health-related information.
  * “Device Information,” such as information your device, browser or operating system automatically provides to us, such as your IP address, geographic location or device ID.
  * Information about your communications with us, such as information regarding any contact you may have with our chat or support teams.

To process your subscription, an order for books, other educational materials, or other items offered as part of our online program, we may require your name, billing address, phone number, email address, and credit card information.  We will protect this information as set forth in this Policy, and in the event Partners perform these services on our behalf, we will ensure they comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Whether you provide us with the voluntary data described above is in your sole discretion.  If you submit PII to us through the Site, then we will use your personal information to operate, maintain, and provide you with the features and functionality of the Site.  We use both your PII and certain non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, cookies, browser type, clickstream data, etc.) to improve the quality and design of the Site and to create new features, functionality, and services by storing, tracking, and analyzing user preferences and trends. 

For purposes of this Policy:

  * “Slimming World” means Slimming World groups and the Site;
  * “Third Party” means a business that is outside the Slimming World family and that is not a Partner; and
  * “Partner” means a business that Slimming World works with to maintain or improve our services, or perform services on our behalf.

Slimming World is the owner of the information collected on this Site.  Except as provided in this Policy, we do not disclose any PII about you to anyone except as permitted by law; however, we may choose to disclose all of the information we collect, other than Health Information, as described above, to Partners that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other Partners with whom we have joint marketing agreements.  Your information may be disclosed to Partners who provide support services to us in relation to those services, such as credit card processors, data processors, technical systems consultants, researchers, statisticians, data analysts, and programmers. In certain circumstances in the future, we may share your Health Information with Partners who are health insurers with whom we work to enhance or provide our services to you. In such an instance, Health Information would only be shared with a health insurer in the event the services we provide to you are through, or in connection with, your plan or coverage offered by that insurer. In the event Slimming World decides to conduct research studies, you may also be invited to enroll in one or more studies, in which case you would be asked to complete a separate research informed consent form.

Slimming World may share aggregate information about our users with advertisers, sponsors and other Third Parties, though such summary information will not include PII or identifiable Health Information.  We may also provide analysis based on the information we collect to our Partners.  We may use the PII you provide to administer Site usage and monitor traffic-levels, and to contact you regarding improvements we can make to our Site and our services, if necessary. We also may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Site, track user movement, and link to other information about you to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.  As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets and, depending on the transaction, your PII may be one of the transferred assets. Similarly, if Slimming World should ever merge with or be acquired by another company, we may share your personal information with any entity resulting from such transaction and if Slimming World should ever file for bankruptcy, the bankruptcy trustee has the right to sell the information you provide to us, provided the sale of such information is permitted by law, to a Third Party..

We may use your email address to contact you directly regarding services, products or information that we believe might interest you.  Only Slimming World or our Partners will send you these direct mailings. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you enroll. Or, at any time you can easily opt-out of receiving further marketing from Slimming World by logging in to the website, visiting your ‘settings’ and updating your preferences.

Transactional emails (e.g. receipts, notifications about your membership) will continue to be delivered to you during your active membership, regardless of whether you have opting into receiving marketing and support emails.

Slimming World may disclose PII when required by law or legal process; when necessary to protect and defend the rights or property of Slimming World; or when necessary to protect the personal safety of Slimming World website users and customers.

We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. 

### 2\. Your Disclosure Choices

You may, of course, decline to submit PII through the Site, in which case Slimming World may not be able to provide certain services to you.  To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before creating your user account.  The user that created the account for a user is responsible for maintaining the secrecy of the unique password and account information at all times. 

### 3\. Public Forums

The Site utilizes public and private chat groups, which may include blogs, forums, comments, message boards, chat rooms and other interactive features.  Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas is not protected as confidential and becomes public information, and Slimming World cannot control its use.  You are solely responsible and should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information in these areas. Please see our Terms of Use for more about your responsibilities and obligations associated with using our public forums.

### 4\. Cookies

We use cookies (a small data file that certain websites write to your hard drive when you visit them), log files, clear gifs or web beacons (known as action tags or single pixel gifs) information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information such as the services you subscribe to; and (c) to assess the popularity and effectiveness of the material posted on the Site. We may also use web beacons in connection with e-mails sent to users, to let us know whether and when the e-mail was opened. No personal information is transmitted through web beacons.

If you refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser, you will not be able to log-in to the site and therefore you will not be able to use the Slimming World online service.

### 5\. Competitions, Drawings and other Postings

By participating in Site competitions, questionnaires, surveys, drawings, posting on the Site groups or chat rooms and commenting on features, you agree that Slimming World may use this information for any purposes, including but not limited to marketing and promotional purposes. 

### 6\. Confidentiality of Transmissions

Please remember that transmissions on the Internet are not always confidential.  You are transmitting this information at your own risk. 

### 7\. Opting Out of Communications, Do Not Track

If you prefer that we not disclose PII about you to Third Parties for advertising or marketing purposes, you may opt out of those disclosures; that is, you may direct us not to make those disclosures (other than disclosures permitted by law).  If you receive communications from us that you do not want to receive, you can opt-out from receiving these communications, by specifically telling us to stop sending them to you. 

We will generally be able to give effect to your withdrawal on 30 days’ notice.  If you wish to opt out of disclosures to Third Parties, you may email your request to Slimming World at [support.team@slimmingworld.com](mailto:support.team@slimmingworld.com).

**“Do Not Track” and Ad Choices:**  There are many mechanisms you can use to manage how we and other parties can monitor your activity on our Site and elsewhere on the Internet. One option is by using “Do Not Track,” a voluntary program among operators of commercial websites and online services that is intended to give users the ability to opt-out of such tracking. We do not currently take actions to respond to Do Not Track signals because there is no uniform definition as to what constitutes a Do Not Track signal, no technological standard with regard to how to respond to any such signals, and no consensus as to what adherence to Do Not Track entails.

AdChoices enables you to opt-out of the collection and use of your information in online behavioral advertising.  We do not currently serve ads on our Site, and therefore to AdChoices does not apply to our activities.

**Slimming World Online Support Emails.  ** As part of our service to Slimming World Online members, to support you in your weight loss, we provide a series of emails throughout your membership. These start with a welcome and membership confirmation e-mail, and also include weighing in reminders and weekly support emails. You’ll be given the opportunity to opt-out to receiving these e-mails on the settings page. Although our supportive e-mails are part of our service to you, you can opt-out or change your preferences at any time.

**Slimming World Online Hall of Fame Posts.   **To publicly celebrate Slimming World Online members’ success, the Site includes a ‘Hall of Fame’ feature which lists the names and weight losses of those members who have achieved the top weight losses that week or month.  You’ll be given the opportunity to opt-in to appearing in the Hall of Fame during your registration and you can opt-out at any time.

### 8\. Security

Information you elect to post on the Site, e-mails and other information you send to us is not encrypted and such transmissions cannot be considered a secure means of transmitting sensitive information.  You should be aware of the limitations of security, authentication, and privacy measures used in connection with the Internet and that any information you transmit through the Site may be damaged, corrupted, "sniffed" and/or accessed by another person without your permission.

Slimming World has reasonable security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control. We safeguard the security of the data you send us with physical, electronic, and other procedures. Regardless of the precautions taken by you or by us, “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet. Others may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the site.  Therefore, although we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.  We cannot ensure or warrant the ultimate security of any information you transmit. 

### 9\. Linked Sites and Third Party Vendors

The Site may contain links to other sites.  Please be aware that Slimming World may not be responsible for content or the privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site and recommend that they read the privacy statements of each and every website they visit.  This Policy applies solely to information collected by this Site.

### 10\. Age Restrictions; Children’s Privacy

This Site is not directed at children under the age of 18 and does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 18.  If Slimming World obtains actual knowledge that it has obtained personal information about an individual under the age of 18, that information is immediately and permanently deleted from our records. Should you, as a parent or legal guardian of a minor, become aware that a user who is under the age of 18 has provided Slimming World with PII, please contact us at the address below to have such account, and the information associated with it, removed.

To delete your account:

  * You can send an email, with the subject line, “Delete My Account,” to [support.team@slimmingworld.com](mailto:support.team@slimmingworld.com); or
  * You can send mail to the following postal address:

Slimming World  
2404 B S. Stemmons Hwy.  
Lewisville, TX 75067

### 11\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time by posting the changes on this page, and we will alert you to such changes by posting a notice on the home page. Any changes will become effective as soon as posted. Your continued use of the Site after the Privacy Policy has been updated will serve as your acceptance of the new Policy.

### 12\. Update Your Account

Slimming World provides users the following options for changing and modifying information previously submitted.

  * You can log in to your Slimming World Online account, visit ‘My Slimming World’ and ‘update my details’ to modify your name, e-mail address, payment details, postal address and many other preferences; or
  * You can send an email, with the subject line “Update My Account,” to [support.team@slimmingworld.com](mailto:support.team@slimmingworld.com); or
  * You can send mail to the following postal address:

Slimming World  
2404 B S. Stemmons Hwy.  
Lewisville, TX 75067

### 13\. Contact Information

If you have a comment, question or request, or if you need to contact Slimming World for any other reason, feel free to contact us using the chat feature, or by using one of the following other methods:

  * You can email us at: [support.team@slimmingworld.com](mailto:support.team@slimmingworld.com)
  * You may call us at (877) 921-7546 during our normal business hours. Normal business hours are Monday through Friday, 8:00 a.m. to 10:00 p.m. and Saturday to Sunday 9:00 a.m. to 2:00 p.m. Central Standard Time (CST).
  * Send mail to Slimming World at:  

Slimming World  
2404 B S. Stemmons Hwy.  
Lewisville, TX 75067
